* Our Story
* Our Team
* Resources

Privacy Policy
--------------

Privacy Policy
--------------

This policy was last updated on February 8, 2021.

### Purpose

It is the established policy of Nieuwland Feed & Supply Ltd. to respect and protect the right to privacy of our visitors and to be compliant with all applicable laws and best professional practices pertaining to the same.

### Who we are

Our website address is: https://nieuwlandfeed.com.

### What data do we collect?

We collect the data necessary to service our website users. This data includes contact information and service preferences, and other data related to the conduct of the business of Nieuwland Feed & Supply Ltd.

### How and why do we collect it?

**Analytics**

We use MonsterInsights WordPress plugin that provides Google analytics services: https://policies.google.com/privacy

Website users who don’t want their data collected with Google Analytics can install the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on at: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout

**Comments**

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

**Comply with Law**

To comply with legal obligations, as part of our general business operations, and for other business administration purposes.

**Cookies**

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

**Embedded content from other websites**

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

**Forms**

**1\. Contact Forms** – We keep contact form submissions for a 1 year period for customer service purposes, but we do not use the information submitted through them for marketing purposes.

**2\. Email Marketing Opt-In Forms** – All email marketing opt-in forms used on this site, such as popups, floating bars, inline-forms, and others, require explicit consent from users before adding them to our mailing list. This is done with either:

A checkbox that user has to click before opt-in; or,  
Requiring double-optin to your email list  
Information gathered is used strictly for that purpose for which it was intended. We do not share the information submitted on an opt-in form with any third parties.

Subscribers to email marketing my unsubscribe at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any email.

**3\. Marketing and Promotions**

For marketing and promotional purposes, such as to send you news and newsletters, special offers, and promotions, or to otherwise contact you about products or information we think may interest you, including information about third party products and services.

**4\. Media**

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

**5\. Prevent Misuse**

Where we believe necessary to investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person or violations of our [Terms of Service](https://nieuwlandfeed.com/terms-of-use) or this Privacy Policy.

**6\. Provide our Services**

To provide you the services we offer on the website, communicate with you about your use of the website, respond to your inquiries, provide troubleshooting, and for other customer service purposes.

### Who do we share your data with?

Your data is shared with third parties who help us to analyze data, follow-up with you and provide better customer service to you including:  
Google Analytics: https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites  
Contact Form 7: https://contactform7.com/privacy-policy/

### How Long Do We Retain Your Data?

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

While laws like the GDPR and CCPA have “right to erasure,” we are not required to erase records needed for other aspects of our business such as: charges disputed by a customer, tax audition, or for other legal concerns. [View Terms of Use.](https://nieuwlandfeed.com/terms-of-use)

We keep contact form entries for six months, analytics records for a year, and customer purchase records for ten years.

### What rights do you have over your data?

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

**GDPR and CCPA User Data Request**

Should you wish to have data access, have data forgotten or data rectfied in comments, posts and our database, please submit a request using the [contact form.](https://nieuwlandfeed.com/contact)

### Where do we send your data?

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service, such as Askimet: https://automattic.com/privacy/

### How do we protect your data?

Nieuwland Feed & Supply Ltd maintains both hard copy and web based data entry form as applicable to the conduct of the business. Online form data is collected and transmitted by secure means. Online form submissions are stored in secure databases with limited access and any sensitive information is encrypted for another layer of protection. We periodically update our membership database using a variety of means to ensure delivery of all publications/correspondence and to better model the demographics of Nieuwland Feed & Supply Ltd.

Users’ data is also protected by our SSL Certificate (Strong SHA2 & 2048-bit encryption), McAfee SECURE (which scans and certifies our website), Website Security Essentials (malware scan and removal), Google Re-Captcha v3 (two-factor authentication), and staff training in data protection.

### What data breach procedures do we have in place?

We are required to report certain types of data breaches to relevant authorities within 72 hours, unless the breach is considered harmless and poses no risk to individual data. However if a breach is high-risk, then we must also inform individuals who are impacted right away.

### What third parties do we receive data from?

We may receive data from:

Facebook Advertising when using the Facebook pixel placed on ads in Facebook and/or Instagram.  
Privacy: https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation  
Cookies: https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/  
Google Analytics: https://policies.google.com/privacy

### What automated decision making and/or profiling do we do with user data?

No automated decision making occurs on this website.

### Who on our team has access?

Administrators on our team have access to the information you provide us to support you.

### How do you contact Nieuwland Feed & Supply Ltd.?

Individuals may contact us if you have concerns about privacy or if you wish to opt-out of any or all hard copy and/or electronic correspondence not explicitly related to requests for services.

Nieuwland Feed & Supply Ltd. may be contacted by mail at the following address:

96 Wellington St N,  
Drayton, ON N0G 1P0

or

5 Line 81  
Listowel, ON  N4W 1Y2

or, by filling in the form on the [Contact page](https://nieuwlandfeed.com/contact).

### Updates

Nieuwland Feed & Supply Ltd. will update this policy and post the updated policy to the Nieuwland Feed & Supply website.

#### Menu

#### Legal

#### Hours

Mon – Fri:  9am-5pm  
Saturday:  8am-12pm  
Sunday:  closed

#### Contact Us

96 Wellington St N,  
Drayton, ON N0G 1P0  
Phone:  [(519) 638-3008](tel://5196383008)

5595 Line 81  
Listowel, ON N4W 1Y2  
Phone:  [(519) 291-5795](tel://5192915795)

Copyright © Nieuwland Feed & Supply Ltd. | Design by [Momentum Marketing](https://momentummarketing.co/)

7457 hwy 17  
West Warren, ON  
705-967-2064

23 John Street  
Sunridge, On  
705-384-5365

31 Main Street  
Thornloe, ON  
705-563-2555

1497 Alderdale Rd  
Powassan, ON  
705-724-1497

We use cookies on our website to give you the most relevant experience by remembering your preferences and repeat visits. By clicking “Accept All”, you consent to the use of ALL the cookies. However, you may visit "Cookie Settings" to provide a controlled consent.

Cookie SettingsAccept All

Manage consent

Close

#### Privacy Overview

This website uses cookies to improve your experience while you navigate through the website. Out of these, the cookies that are categorized as necessary are stored on your browser as they are essential for the working of basic functionalities of the website. We also use third-party cookies that help us analyze and understand how you use this website. These cookies will be stored in your browser only with your consent. You also have the option to opt-out of these cookies. But opting out of some of these cookies may affect your browsing experience.

Necessary

 Necessary

Always Enabled

Necessary cookies are absolutely essential for the website to function properly. These cookies ensure basic functionalities and security features of the website, anonymously.

| Cookie | Duration | Description |
| --- | --- | --- |
| cookielawinfo-checkbox-analytics | 11 months | This cookie is set by GDPR Cookie Consent plugin. The cookie is used to store the user consent for the cookies in the category "Analytics". |
| cookielawinfo-checkbox-functional | 11 months | The cookie is set by GDPR cookie consent to record the user consent for the cookies in the category "Functional". |
| cookielawinfo-checkbox-necessary | 11 months | This cookie is set by GDPR Cookie Consent plugin. The cookies is used to store the user consent for the cookies in the category "Necessary". |
| cookielawinfo-checkbox-others | 11 months | This cookie is set by GDPR Cookie Consent plugin. The cookie is used to store the user consent for the cookies in the category "Other. |
| cookielawinfo-checkbox-performance | 11 months | This cookie is set by GDPR Cookie Consent plugin. The cookie is used to store the user consent for the cookies in the category "Performance". |
| viewed\_cookie\_policy | 11 months | The cookie is set by the GDPR Cookie Consent plugin and is used to store whether or not user has consented to the use of cookies. It does not store any personal data. |

Functional

 Functional

Functional cookies help to perform certain functionalities like sharing the content of the website on social media platforms, collect feedbacks, and other third-party features.

Performance

 Performance

Performance cookies are used to understand and analyze the key performance indexes of the website which helps in delivering a better user experience for the visitors.

Analytics

 Analytics

Analytical cookies are used to understand how visitors interact with the website. These cookies help provide information on metrics the number of visitors, bounce rate, traffic source, etc.

Advertisement

 Advertisement

Advertisement cookies are used to provide visitors with relevant ads and marketing campaigns. These cookies track visitors across websites and collect information to provide customized ads.

Others

 Others

Other uncategorized cookies are those that are being analyzed and have not been classified into a category as yet.

SAVE & ACCEPT
